# **James Paolantonio**

#### **PROFILE**

I am a mobile engineer primarily working on Apple's iOS platform. I have a deep understanding of mobile development, as well as mobile user interaction. I have experience working with both small and large teams, as well as cross team communication and product management.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## MOBILE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, COMPASS, INC NOVEMBER 2014 - PRESENT

- Rebuilt consumer version of mobile application to coordinate with DC launch of service.
- · Rebranded entire consumer application for refined look and feel of the new compass.com.
- · Led manual and automated testing practices, including XCTest, CI, snapshot and Jenkins.

SENIOR IOS ENGINEER, THIS LIFE, INC (HOWABOUTWE) JUNE 2013 - JULY 2014 MOBILE ENGINEER, THIS LIFE, INC (HOWABOUTWE) JUNE 2012 - JUNE 2013

- Stabilized first version of HowAboutWe Dating's original iPhone application.
- Built first version of HowAboutWe Dating's iPad application, which included procedural drawn designs and Core Data.
- Rewrote Dating's second version of their iPhone application, which included all iPad features plus extensive unit (Kiwi) and integration (KIF) tests.
- Implement custom continuous integration server for all our iOS apps.
- Open sourced multiple components built for the iOS platform.
- Led development of You&Me, a messaging application for couples. This included managing feature requirements, coordinating with server teams, and studying user testing.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER, MICROSOFT CORPORATION MAY 2011- AUGUST 2011

- Worked with a small team to create an internal Windows Phone 7 application and Azure server backend used to deploy internal business applications.
- Created internal tool used to facilitate development for mobile web sites, including Microsoft's mobile website m.microsoft.com.

## FOUNDER, JDUB STUDIOS MARCH 2008 - JUNE 2013

- Started a profitable mobile design and development company.
- · Developed over twenty mobile applications approved on Apple's App Store.

## **EDUCATION**

## THE PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY GRADUATED MAY 2012

B.S Information Science and Technology - Information Systems, Design & Development Minor in Engineering Entrepreneurship

#### SKILLS

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Objective-C, C, Swift, Java, Ruby, SQL

#### OTHER

Xcode, Git, Cocoa, CocoaTouch, Core Data, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, TDD, Continuous Integration, Facebook API